Francisco Hernández | CV

☐ +56 9 8822 1074 • ☑ fthernan@uc.cl • ② https://fthernan.github.io

Objectives

Autodidact and passionate about science, arts and interaction design. With a strong background in physics and computer science, my goal is to further research in data analysis & visualization, human-computer interaction and wearable sensing devices. I look forward to apply these areas in order to create new devices that will improve people's life quality.

Education

Instituto Nacional Gral. José Miguel Carrera

Secondary education

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Licentiate degree in Physics, Upper second-class honours.

Thesis: "Preliminary studies of exploding wires in a Plasma Focus"

Santiago, Chile

December 2009

Santiago, Chile

January 2017

Academic experience

Research, Teaching.

Research Assistant in Plasma Laboratory

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

April 2014 - present

Among the tasks performed is the creation of electronics to control pulsed-power experiments, obtaining & analyzing spectra of plasma emission and realizing various optics diagnostics.

Also, these practices where realized at the Institute of Physics:

- Winter practice: "Optical diagnostics in dense transient plasmas" July 2014
- Summer practice: "Transient atmospheric plasmas with applications in industry and medicine" January 2015

Assistantship at Laboratory and Tutor

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

March 2015 - November 2016

Assistantship at Laboratory, Institute of Physics: "Physics for science" (FIS109), "Thermodynamics" (FIS152), "Electricity and Magnetism" (FIS0153) and "Electronics for Physicists" (FIZ3300).

Tutor, Institute of Physics: "Introduction to Programming" (IIC1103) - 2015

Science communication

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

March 2015 - November 2016

Worked in several science, technology, and university fairs.

Participation in projects or research programs.....

Monolith Controversies

Santiago, Chile

National Council of Culture and the Arts (Chile)

November 2013 - July 2014

Chilean Pavilion at the 14th Venice Architecture Biennale. Developed a system for audiovisual media for the pavilion.

The Chilean Pavilion was awarded with the Silver Lion,

Achievements

o Winner at BRAIN (Business, Research, Acceleration and Innovation) Chile.

Khapto was one of the 10 awarded startups between 325 scientific & technology projects. August, 2016. Santiago, Chile.

International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) contestant.

Selected to represent Chile at the IOI in 2008 (El Cairo, Egypt) and 2009 (Plovdiv, Bulgaria).

 1st Place in VI IEEE Chilean Robotics Competition in Open Category November, 2007. Monterrey, Mexico.

 \circ 1st Place in VI IEEE Chilean Robotics Competition in Open Category

October, 2007. Santiago, Chile.

Skills

- **Programming languages, syntaxes and/or libraries:** C/C++, Python, Matlab, Arduino, HTML, Javascript, ES6, SQL, PHP, MySQL, Lagent MySQL, LibCinder, React Native, CUDA, scikit-learn.
- o **Software:** Visual Studio, Matlab, Xcode, LTspice, Microsoft Office, Rhinoceros 3D, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Git, Eagle.
- o Other skills: 3D printing, CNC fabrication, PCBA design and fabrication, mathematical modeling.
- o Languages: Advanced English (IELTS: 7), Native Spanish.

Work experience

CTO Santiago, Chile

Khapto May 2016 - present

Startup which objective is to improve the way physiotherapy is realized. Through the use of different sensors in a wearable device, we provide the professional with a series of critical data that allow a more effective improvement of the patient. This, in a larger scale, will allow massive studies about injuries and treatments.

Programming and mathematics consultant

Santiago, Chile

o Dirección de Extensión y Servicios Externos (DESE) Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Estudios Urbanos UC July 2017 - August 2017

Advice on the development of software that automatically generates, through Monte-Carlo simulations, the average price of different types of buildings. The software was developed for the Internal Revenue Service of Chile.

Hardware and software developer

Santiago, Chile

Freelancer

2015

Design and development of a remote water level system for irrigation channel. An ultra-sensitive capacitive sensor was developed and through GSM the data was sent to a web server in order to be visualized in a website.

Interactive mobile app developer

Santiago, Chile

o Dirección de Extensión y Servicios Externos (DESE) Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Estudios Urbanos UC March 2015 - August 2015

Development of a solution for the National Monuments Council of Chile consisting in a hybrid mobile App to register properties and national monuments, with a web-based management capable of generate automated reports.

Interactive Software developer

Santiago, Chile

Guillermo Acuña Arquitectos Asociados

September 2012 - April 2013

Design and development of an interactive software for an exhibition in the MAXXI museum, Rome. The project proposes to visualize data about the city of Santiago on which a project of optimization of energies is proposed. As part of the team I developed all the software, visualizations and data analysis.

Interactive software & hardware developer and experience designer Frankenstudio | Etnolab SpA

Santiago, Chile

2011-2012

Responsible of the development of software and hardware for several projects and designing of interactive experiences. Some of the works includes:

- Interactive video wall with body recognition
- Educative game with on touch-screen
- Interactive installation with natural interaction using hand recognition and 3D capture
- Installation in museum on digital platforms
- Interactive installation in public street with web interaction
- Design and building of hardware

Web developer Santiago, Chile
Freelancer 2009–2011

Development of several websites and programming of an own CMS (Content Management System) to provide an easier management. Worked with PHP, MySQL, JS, HTML y CSS.